[
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "What is Cloud Computing?",
    "prompt": "<p>What is the main advantage of Cloud Computing?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>It's main advantage is that it is not constrained by physical infrastructure.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "What is Cloud Computing?",
    "prompt": "<p>Define Cloud Computing</p>",
    "answer": "<p>The delivery of computing services over the internet.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>In the shared responsibility model. what is the cloud consumer/customer ALWAYS responsible for?</p>",
    "answer": "\"\t<ul>    <li>Information and Data: stored in the cloud.</li>    <li>Devices (Mobile and PCs): allowed to connect to the cloud.</li>    <li>Accounts and Identities: of people services and devices within your organisation.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>In the shared responsibility model. what is the cloud provider ALWAYS responsible for?</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>The physical datacenter</li><li>The physical network.</li><li>The physical hosts.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Who's responsible for <b>Information and Data</b> in the shared responsibility model when using each of the following:</p><ul>    <li>SaaS</li>    <li>PaaS</li>    <li>IaaS</li>    <li>On-premises</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>SaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>PaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>IaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>On-premises: Cloud Consumer</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Who's responsible for <b>Devices (Mobiles. PCs. etc)</b> in the shared responsibility model when using each of the following:</p><ul>    <li>SaaS</li>    <li>PaaS</li>    <li>IaaS</li>    <li>On-premises</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>SaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>PaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>IaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>On-premises: Cloud Consumer</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Who's responsible for <b>Accounts and Identities</b> in the shared responsibility model when using each of the following:</p><ul>    <li>SaaS</li>    <li>PaaS</li>    <li>IaaS</li>    <li>On-premises</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>SaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>PaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>IaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>On-premises: Cloud Consumer</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Who's responsible for <b>Identity and Directory Infrastructure</b> in the shared responsibility model when using each of the following:</p><ul>    <li>SaaS</li>    <li>PaaS</li>    <li>IaaS</li>    <li>On-premises</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>SaaS: Shared Responsibility</li>    <li>PaaS: Shared Responsibility</li>    <li>IaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>On-premises: Cloud Consumer</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Who's responsible for <b>Applications</b> in the shared responsibility model when using each of the following:</p><ul>    <li>SaaS</li>    <li>PaaS</li>    <li>IaaS</li>    <li>On-premises</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>SaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>PaaS: Shared Responsibility</li>    <li>IaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>On-premises: Cloud Consumer</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Who's responsible for <b>Network Controls</b> in the shared responsibility model when using each of the following:</p><ul>    <li>SaaS</li>    <li>PaaS</li>    <li>IaaS</li>    <li>On-premises</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>SaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>PaaS: Shared Responsibility</li>    <li>IaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>On-premises: Cloud Consumer</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Who's responsible for <b>Operating System</b> in the shared responsibility model when using each of the following:</p><ul>    <li>SaaS</li>    <li>PaaS</li>    <li>IaaS</li>    <li>On-premises</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>SaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>PaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>IaaS: Cloud Consumer</li>    <li>On-premises: Cloud Consumer</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Who's responsible for <b>Physical Hosts</b> in the shared responsibility model when using each of the following:</p><ul>    <li>SaaS</li>    <li>PaaS</li>    <li>IaaS</li>    <li>On-premises</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>SaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>PaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>IaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>On-premises: Cloud Consumer</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Who's responsible for <b>Physical Network</b> in the shared responsibility model when using each of the following:</p><ul>    <li>SaaS</li>    <li>PaaS</li>    <li>IaaS</li>    <li>On-premises</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>SaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>PaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>IaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>On-premises: Cloud Consumer</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "The Shared Responsibility Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Who's responsible for <b>Physical Datacenter</b> in the shared responsibility model when using each of the following:</p><ul>    <li>SaaS</li>    <li>PaaS</li>    <li>IaaS</li>    <li>On-premises</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>SaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>PaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>IaaS: Cloud Provider</li>    <li>On-premises: Cloud Consumer</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Private Cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A cloud built controlled and maintained by a single entity.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>When it comes to infrastructure a private cloud requires?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>It requires the infrastructure to be on a private network.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Advantages of Private Cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Complete control over resources and security.</li>    <li>Data is not colocated with other organisations data</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Disadvantages of Private Cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Upfront CapEx cost: hardware must be purchased for startup and maintenance.</li>    <li>Lacks the benefits of public cloud.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Public Cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A cloud built controlled and maintained by a third-party provider. Anyone that wants to purchase cloud services can access and use resources. This availability is a key difference between other cloud models.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Advantages of Public Cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>No capital expenditures to scale up</li>    <li>Applications can be quickly provisioned and deprovisioned</li>    <li>Organizations pay only for what they use</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Disadvantages of Public Cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Organizations don't have complete control over resources and security.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Hybrid Cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Cloud based on an on-premises architecture and a public cloud - or a private cloud and a public cloud.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Some use cases for Hybrid Cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Typically used when leveraging benefits of running applications from a public cloud while providing additional security by storing data in a private cloud - or to allow a private cloud to surge for increase or temporary demand by deploying public cloud resources.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Advantages of Hybrid Cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Provides the most flexibility.</li>    <li>Organisations can determine where to run their applications.</li>    <li>Cost-effectiveness of ability to scale</li><li>Eases the process of cloud transition.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Disadvantages of Hybrid Cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Complexity of Management & Implementation</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Define Cloud Models",
    "prompt": "<p>Multi-cloud</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Uses features from many cloud providers - you deal with two (or more) public cloud providers and manage resources and security in both environments.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Describe the Consumption-based Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Capital Expenditure (CapEx)</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Typically a one-time. up-front expenditure to purchase or secure tangible resources.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Describe the Consumption-based Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Operational Expenditure (OpEx)</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Typically spending money on services or products over time.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Describe the Consumption-based Model",
    "prompt": "<p>What are the two types of expenses to consider when comparing IT infrastructure models?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Capital Expenditure and Operational Expenditure</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Describe the Consumption-based Model",
    "prompt": "<p>Benefits of the Consumption Based Model</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>No upfront costs.</li>    <li>No need to purchase and manage costly infrastructure that users might not use to its fullest potential.</li>    <li>The ability to pay for more resources when they're needed.</li>    <li>The ability to stop paying for resources that are no longer needed.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Computing",
    "topic": "Describe the Consumption-based Model",
    "prompt": "<p>When is the consumption based model not the most efficient one?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>It is the less efficient expenditure model when an organisation has a consitent - high utilisation of compute, storage, and network resources.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of High Availability and Scalability",
    "prompt": "<p>High Availability</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Focuses on ensuring maximum uptime. regardless of disruptions or events that may occur. Solutions must account for service availability guarantees. These are part of the Service Level Agreements (SLAs).</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of High Availability and Scalability",
    "prompt": "<p>Scalability</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Refers to the ability to adjust resources to meet demand.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of High Availability and Scalability",
    "prompt": "<p>Service Level Agreement (SLA)</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A formal agreement between service provider and customer ensuring a certain level of service.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of High Availability and Scalability",
    "prompt": "<p>How Azure represents its SLAs.</p>",
    "answer": "<p>As a percentage of uptime for a service.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of High Availability and Scalability",
    "prompt": "<p>The two types of scalability and their meaning.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Horizontal: Adding or subtracting from the total number of resources.</li>    <li>Vertical: Increasing the capabilities of exisiting resources.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of High Availability and Scalability",
    "prompt": "<p>Horizontal Scaling</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Adding or subtracting from the total number of resources.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of High Availability and Scalability",
    "prompt": "<p>Vertical Scaling</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Increasing the capabilities of exisiting resources.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of High Availability and Scalability",
    "prompt": "<p>Benefits of scalability.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Ability to adjust resources to meet demand.</li>    <li>Don't overpay for underutilised/overutilized services.</li>    <li>You only pay for what you use.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Cloud",
    "prompt": "<p>The seven major benefits of using cloud services.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>High Availability</li>    <li>Scalability</li>    <li>Reliability</li>    <li>Predictability</li>    <li>Security</li>    <li>Governance</li>    <li>Manageability</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Reliability and Predictability",
    "prompt": "<p>Reliability</p>",
    "answer": "<p>The ability of a system to recover from failures and continue to function.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Reliability and Predictability",
    "prompt": "<p>At a high level. how does Azure ensure Reliability for its consumers?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A decentralised design enables Azure cloud to deploy resources and backups around the world. thereby enabling failover even when experiencing a catastrophic event in an entire region.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Reliability and Predictability",
    "prompt": "<p>The two main areas of Azure Cloud Predictability.</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Performance and Cost.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Reliability and Predictability",
    "prompt": "<p>Examples of Azure services and features which support performance predictability.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Autoscaling</li>    <li>Load Balancing</li>    <li>High Availability</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Reliability and Predictability",
    "prompt": "<p>Azure cloud tools that can estimate potential cloud spend.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Total Cost of Ownership (TCO).</li>    <li>Pricing Calculator.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Reliability and Predictability",
    "prompt": "<p>How cloud supports cost predictability.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Track resource use in real time.</li>    <li>Monitor resources to ensure efficeint use.</li>    <li>Apply data analytics to find patterns for planning better resource deployment.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Reliability and Predictability",
    "prompt": "<p>Cost Predictability</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Focuses on predicting or forecasting the cost of the cloud spend.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Security and Governance",
    "prompt": "<p>Examples of how Azure enables sound Governance.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Ability to set templates to ensure that all deployed resources meet corportate and government regulatory requirements.</li>    <li>Ability to update all deployed resources to new standards as they change.</li>    <li>Cloud-based auditing to flag resources which are out of compliance.</li>    <li>Automatic application of software patches and updates.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Security and Governance",
    "prompt": "<p>At a high level. how does Azure enable robust Security.</p>",
    "answer": "<p>At a high level. how does Azure enable robust Security.</p><ul>    <li>Allows consumers to choose the level of security control (i.e. The IaaS model enables manual access to OS. software patches etc. whereas PaaS automatically takes care of updates for you).</li>    <li>Cloud providers are typically more well suited to handle common security events like Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attacks.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Manageability",
    "prompt": "<p>The two types of manageability for cloud computing.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Management <b>of</b> the cloud: Managing your cloud environment and resources.</li>    <li>Management <b>in</b> the cloud: How you are able to manage your cloud environment and resources</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe the Benefits of Using Cloud Services",
    "topic": "Benefits of Manageability",
    "prompt": "<p>What tools are available to manage your cloud environment.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Through the Web Portal.</li>    <li>Using a Command Line Interface.</li>    <li>Using APIs.</li>    <li>Using PowerShell.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Service Types",
    "topic": "Describe Infrastructure as a Service",
    "prompt": "<p>Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Cloud provider is responsible for maintaining hardware. network connectivity. and physical security. <br /> The consumer is responsible for everything else.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Service Types",
    "topic": "Describe Infrastructure as a Service",
    "prompt": "<p>Biggest benefit of IaaS</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Provides the most flexibility. the maximum amount of control for cloud resources.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Service Types",
    "topic": "Describe Infrastructure as a Service",
    "prompt": "<p>Scenarios in which IaaS is used.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Lift and Shift migration: standing up cloud resources to migrate to.</li>    <li>You have established configs for development and test environments that need to rapidly replicate.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Service Types",
    "topic": "Describe Platform as a Service",
    "prompt": "<p>In Platform as a Service (PaaS). the cloud provider maintains:</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Physical infrastructure. security. and networks (inc. internet connection). and</li>    <li>The operating systems. databses. and development tools.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Service Types",
    "topic": "Describe Platform as a Service",
    "prompt": "<p>Biggest benefit of PaaS</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Provides a complete development environment without the headache of maintaining all the development infrastructure.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Service Types",
    "topic": "Describe Platform as a Service",
    "prompt": "<p>Scenarios in which PaaS is used.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Development framework: PaaS provides a framework that developers can build upon to develop or customize cloud-based applications. PaaS lets developers create applications using built-in software components.</li>    <li>Analytics or business intelligence Tools provided as a service with PaaS allow organizations to analyze and mine their data. finding insights and patterns and predicting outcomes to improve forecasting. product design decisions. investment returns. and other business decisions.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Service Types",
    "topic": "Describe Software as a Service",
    "prompt": "<p>Software as a Service (SaaS)</p>",
    "answer": "<p>The most complete cloud service model. from a product perspective. With SaaS. you're essentially renting or using a fully developed application. Email . financial software. messaging applications. and connectivity software are all common examples of a SaaS implementation</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Service Types",
    "topic": "Describe Software as a Service",
    "prompt": "<p>Biggest benefit of SaaS</p>",
    "answer": "<p>While the SaaS model may be the least flexible. it's also the easiest to get up and running. It require the least amount of technical knowledge or expertise to fully employ.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Service Types",
    "topic": "Describe Software as a Service",
    "prompt": "<p>In Software as a Service (SaaS). the cloud provider is responsible for:</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Everything apart from:</li>    <li>The data you put into the system.</li>    <li>The devices you allow to connect to the system. and the users that have access.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Cloud Concepts",
    "module": "Describe Cloud Service Types",
    "topic": "Describe Software as a Service",
    "prompt": "<p>Scenarios in which SaaS is used.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul>    <li>Email and Messaging.</li>    <li>Business productivity applications.</li>    <li>Finance and expense tracking.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },




  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Azure Accounts",
    "prompt": "<p>What is the Heirarchy of Azure Account Components</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Account (Tenant)</li><li>Management Groups</li><li>Subscription/s</li><li>Resource Group/s</li><li>Resource/s</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Azure Accounts",
    "prompt": "<p>What is included in the Azure Free Account?</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>12 months free access to popular Azure services</li><li>Credit to use in the first 30 days</li><li>Access to more than 25 products that are always free.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Azure Accounts",
    "prompt": "<p>What is included in the Azure Student Account?</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Similar to the Free account, plus:</li><li>$100 Credit to use in the first <b>12 months</b></li><li>Access to additional software development tools for free</li><li>No credit card required</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Region</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Geographical area on the planet that contains at least one, but potentially many datacenters which are nearby and networked together with low-latency. Some Azure features are only available in certain regions.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Availability Zone</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Physically seperate datacenters within an Azure region. Each is made up of one or more datacenters with independent power, cooling, and networking.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Define an Isolation Boundary. Give an example of a physical component which utilises one.</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Availability Zones utililise isolation boundaries so that when one datacenter goes down the other continues to work.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>What is the minimum number of availability zones in a zone-enabled region?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A minimum of three are set yp to ensure resiliency. Not all regions support them.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>What are Availability Zones typically used for?</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>To protect data against failure</li><li>Ensure redundancy</li><li>and building high-availabilty into mission critical applications</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>List the three categories that Azure services utilising availability zones fall into.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Zonal Services</li><li>Zone-redundant services</li><li>Non-regional services</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Zonal Services</p>",
    "answer": "<p>You pin the resource to a specific zone (for example, VMs, managed disks, IP addresses)</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Zone-redundant Services</p>",
    "answer": "<p>The platform replicates automatically across zones (for example, zone-redundant storage, SQL Database).</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Non-regional services</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Services are always available from Azure geographies and are resilient to zone-wide outages as well as region-wide outages.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Region Pairs</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Most Azure regions are paired with another within the same geography at least 300 miles (480km) away to enable replication and reduce the impact of large scale outages (eg. natural disasters). This is not always automatic and should be configured by the customer.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Advantages of Region Pairs</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Replication and therefore resiliency to large scale outages</li><li>In event of large outage, one region is prioritised for quickest restore</li><li>Planned Azure updates are rolled out to one of these one at a time to minimise downtime and outage.</li><li>Data stays within its geography for tax and law-enforcement, jurisdiction purposes.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Physical Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Sovereign Regions</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Instances of Azure that are isolated from the main instance of Azure. Mainly used for legal purposes.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Components of the Azure Management Infrastructure</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Azure Resources</li><li>Resource Groups</li><li>Subscriptions</li><li>Management Groups</li><li>Accounts</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Azure Resources</p>",
    "answer": "<p>The basic building block of Azure. Anything you create, provision, deploy etc. Virtual Machines(VMs), Virtual networks, databases, cognitive services, etc.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Azure Resource Group</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>A grouping of Azure Resources.</li><li>When creating a resource, you are required to place it into a resource group.</li><li>While a resources group can contain many resources, a single resource can only be in one resource group at a time.</li><li>Resources groups cannot be nested.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>What happens when you apply an action (delete, allow access, etc) to a Resource Groups</p>",
    "answer": "<p>The action effects all of the resources in the resource group ie. deleting a group, deletes all the resources within it.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Azure Subscription</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A unit of management, billing, and scale. They allow you to logically organise resource groups (similar to groups for resources) and facilitate billing.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>What is required to use Azure? What does it provide</p>",
    "answer": "<p>An Azure Subscription. It provides authenticated and authorized access to Azure products and services through Azure Active Directory.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>What is required to use Azure? What does it provide</p>",
    "answer": "<p>An Azure Subscription. It provides authenticated and authorized access to Azure products and services through Azure Active Directory.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Is it possible to have multiple subscriptions in one account? Why would you need it?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Yes, although you only require one, multiple enable the configuration of different billing models and access management policies.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>List the two subscription boundary types</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Billing boundary: determines how an account is billed. Generates seperate billing reports and invoices.</li><li>Access Control Boundary: Seperate subscriptions to reflect different organisational structures (departments).</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Why would you create multiple subscriptions? (3 points)</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>To set up different environments for testing, security, or compliance.</li><li>To reflect organisational structures: limiting some departments but not others</li><li>To easily track costs across needs (production, testing, development)</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Management Group</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A management container for subscriptions that enable governance conditions. All the sub- components, right down to the resources inherity the conditions applied to management groups. These groups can be nested.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>An example of when you would use Management Groups</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Create heirarchy that applies policy: limiting VM locations to a specific region called production.</li><li>Provide cloud users access to multiple subscriptions: by moving the subscriptions under a single management group and using RBAC to assign them to a user, all sub-components, down to the resource, will inherit this access assignment.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Maximum number of Management Groups in single directory</p>",
    "answer": "<p>10,000 are supported in a single directory.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>Maximum nesting for Management Groups</p>",
    "answer": "<p>The Management Groups tree can support up to six levels of depth.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Core Architectural Components",
    "topic": "Management Infrastructure",
    "prompt": "<p>How many parents groups can each management group and subscription have?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Management groups and subscriptions can suppport only one parent.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },





  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Machines",
    "prompt": "<p>Azure Virtual Machines are considered to be what kind of cloud service type?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Virtual machines are considered to be Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS).</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Machines",
    "prompt": "<p>When are Virtual Machines the ideal choice?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>They are the ideal choice when you want:</p><ul><li>Total control over the operating system (OS)</li><li>The ability to run custom software</li><li>To use custom hosting configurations</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Machines",
    "prompt": "<p>The two types of VM scale groupings</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Scale Sets: Create and manage a group of identical, load balanced VMs</li><li>Availability Sets: built for high availability, enables staggered updates by grouping VMs in two ways: Update domains, and Fault domains.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Machines",
    "prompt": "<p>Scale Sets</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Create and manage a group of identical, load balanced VMs</li><li>Automates setup of virtual networks and load monitoring.</li><li>Centrally manage, configure, and update groups of VMs quickly</li><li>Automatically increase or decrease to meet demand or based on defined schedule.</li><li>Useful for large scale service for areas such as compute, big data, and container workloads.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Machines",
    "prompt": "<p>Availability Sets and their two groupings</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Build a more resilient, highly available VM environement group using two methods:</p><ul><li>Update Domain: VMs are grouped so that they are rebooted at the same time, enabling updates to be staggered over these groups (each group gets 30 min to recover before moving to next).</li><li>Fault domain: groups VMs by common power source and network switch. This options by default creates three fault domains.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Machines",
    "prompt": "<p>How much does it cost to create an availability set?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>There is no additional cost for configuration. You only pay for the VMs that you create.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Machines",
    "prompt": "<p>Examples of when to use VMs</p>",
    "answer": "<p>They can be used:</p><ul><li>To move operations to the cloud</li><li>During testing and development to quickly create different OS and application configurations.</li><li>To run applications in the cloud.</li><li>To extending your an existing datacenter to the cloud</li><li>During disaster recovery to for example run mission critical applications until the primary infrastructure becomes operational</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Machines",
    "prompt": "<p>What primary configuration options are available when provisioning a VM?</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Size: purpose, number of processor core, amount of RAM.</li><li>Storage Disks: hard disk drives, solid state drives</li><li>Networking: virtual network, public IP address, port configuration</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Desktop",
    "prompt": "<p>Azure Virtual Desktop</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A type of virtual machine, it is a virtualisation service that enables you to use Windows from any location through the cloud.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Desktop",
    "prompt": "<p>What is AVD enhance security?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Azure Virtual Desktop enhances security by</p><ul><li>Providing centralised security management for user's desktops using Active Directory.</li><li>Seperating data and apps from local hardware, meaning the risk of confidential information being left on a personal device is reduced.</li><li>User sessions are isolated in both single and multi-session environments</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Virtual Desktop",
    "prompt": "<p>What is Multi-session AVD?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Multi-session Azure Virtual Desktop enables concurrent users on a single Windows 10 or 11 VM</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Containers",
    "prompt": "<p>Azure Containers</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A virtualisation environment in which (unlike VMs) the user does not manage the operating system. They are designed to be lightweight and therefore easily scalable to demand.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Containers",
    "prompt": "<p>Azure Container Instances</p>",
    "answer": "<p>The fastest and simplest way to run a container in Azure; wihtou having to manage any virtual machines or adopt any additional services.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Containers",
    "prompt": "<p>Azure Container instances are what kind of Azure service type? (SaaS, PaaS, IaaS, On-prem)</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Azure Container Instances are consided Platform as a Service (PaaS). The service will run the containers you upload for you.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Containers",
    "prompt": "<p>What are Azure containers typically used for?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Typically they are used to create solutions using a microservice architecture (solutions that are broken into smaller, independent pieces). For example, a website may be broken into containers for the front-end and another for the backend, and a third for storage.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Functions",
    "prompt": "<p>Azure Functions</p>",
    "answer": "<p>An Event-Driven, serverless compute option that doesn't require maintaining any virtual machines or containers. An event wakes the function alleviating the need (unlike VMs and containers) to keep resources provisioned when there are no events. .</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Functions",
    "prompt": "<p>Benefits of Azure Functions</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>No infrastructure management (no need to focus on server management)</li><li>Scalability</li><li>Only pay for what you use.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Functions",
    "prompt": "<p>What does it mean that Azure Functions can be stateless or stateful>?</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Stateless: They can behave as if they are restarted everytime they respond to an event</li><li>Stateful: (curable functions) a context is passed through the function to track prior activity.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "AZ-900: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals",
    "section": "Describe Azure Architecture and Services",
    "module": "Describe Compute and Networking Services",
    "topic": "Azure Functions",
    "prompt": "<p>Main purpose of Azure Functions?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A key component of serverless computing. They are a general compute platform for running any type of code.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  }

,
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "The Acyclic Dependencies Principle",
    "prompt": "<p>How can we break the cycles in a dependency graph?</p>",
    "answer": "<ol><li>Apply the Dependency Inversion Principle.</li><li>Create a new component that both objects inherit from.</li></ol>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "Top Down Design",
    "prompt": "<p>Component Diagrams are a map to what two features of a system?</p>",
    "answer": "<ol><li>Buildability.</li><li>Maintainability.</li></ol>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "Principles",
    "prompt": "<p>Define The Stable Dependencies Principle.</p>",
    "answer": "<p><i>Depend in the direction of stability.</i> Modules that are intended to be easy to change should not depend on modules which are harder to change.</p>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "The Stable Dependencies Principle.",
    "prompt": "<p>What is meant by stability?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A module is said to be stable if it is not easily changed. <i>Highly depended apon comonents are stable because it is difficult to change them</i></p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "The Stable Dependencies Principle",
    "prompt": "<p>The three stability metrics.</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li><i>Fan-in</i>: The number of classes <b>inside</b> a component that depend on classes inside the component.</li><li><i>Fan-out</i>: The number of classes <b>outside</b> a component that depend on classes outside the component.</li><li>Instability - <i>I = Fan-out - (Fan-in + Fan-out)</i>. A I vlaue of 1 indicates a maximally unstable component.</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Define"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "The Stable Dependencies Principle",
    "prompt": "<p>Where should we place unstable components in the component diagram and why?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>At the top, because arrows pointing up would then violate SDP and ADP</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "The Stable Dependencies Principle",
    "prompt": "<p>How can we fix an unavoidable violation of the SDP?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>Using the Dependence Inversion Principle (DIP).<br/>By creating an component and interface for the instable component classes we can make the stable class use the dependency without breaking SDP.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "Principles",
    "prompt": "<p>Define The Stable Abstractions Principle (SAP)</p>",
    "answer": "<p>A component should be as abstract as it is stable.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "The Stable Abstractions Principle",
    "prompt": "<p>Where should we put high level policy?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>High level policy should be maximally stable. However, it should also be easily extendible and this is achieved using the OCP. Open for extension, closed for modification. The type of classes that are best suited to these contraints are <i>abstract classes</i>.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "The Stable Abstractions Principle",
    "prompt": "<p>Which component principle is acheived through the combination of SDP and SAP?</p>",
    "answer": "<p>The DIP principle is achieved, as the reuslt is that <i> dependencies run in the direcction of abstraction</i>.</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "The Stable Abstractions Principle",
    "prompt": "<p>How can component abstraction be measured?</p>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>Simply by measureing the ratio of abstraction classes and interfaces to concrete classes.</li><li>A = Na / Nc</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "The Main Sequence",
    "prompt": "<p>What can be said about compnents with the following values of I (instability) and A (abstractness).</p><ul><li>[0,1] stable, abstract</li><li>[1,1] instable, abstract</li><li>[1,0] instable, concrete</li><li>[0,0] stable, concrete</li></ul>",
    "answer": "<ul><li>[0,1] Best suited to high-level policies</li><li>[1,1]The zone of Uselessness: Empty dead code that is not used for anything.</li><li>[1,0] best suited to volotile components like UI</li><li>[0,0] The Zone of Pain: Diffciult to change or extend (database schema)</li></ul>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  },
  {
    "certificate": "Clean Architecture - Robert C. Martin",
    "section": "Components",
    "module": "Component Coupling",
    "topic": "The Main Sequence",
    "prompt": "<p>What is the Distance Metric used for and how is it calculated.</p>",
    "answer": "<p>D = I+A-1 The distance metric determines if a component is close to the main sequence and therefore following good design preactices</p>",
    "promptType": "Question"
  }
]
